Guide to the South African Apartheid Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Additional Material, Accession 2005-M-052
  - "Jacobsens index of objectionable literature from Pretoria", 1908 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Johannesburg 1974/75 [budget report for the year ended 30th June, 1975] (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Kwazulu, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - A Letter from South Africa [monthly viewpoint on South Africa, nos, 1, 3 and 4], 1988 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Mandela buttons, undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Manifest: organ for kommunstisk arbejdsgruppe, 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Nasionale Party (NP) [position paper], 1986 July (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - The New South Africa [brochure published by the South African government], 1990 May (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Newsletter on the oil embargo against South Africa [no.3], 1986 February (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Oranje- perspektief [no. 2.4], 1986 June (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - PAC News [publication of the Pan Africanist Congress of Azania, Australasia and the Pacific office, no.1], 1983 November-December (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Prisma Actueel [journal], undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Scandinavian Newsletter on South Africa (no.1), 1984 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Solidarity News Services, 1983 July 25 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Solidarity with black South African workers [bumper stickers in support of USdivestmentin South Africa], undated (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - South African Congress of Trade Unions (SACTU) Solidarity Committee (Canada), 1985 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - "South African Dossier", 1989 December (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - South African government, department of water affairs, undated (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - The South African Institute of International Affairs, 1994-1995 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - South African Institute of Race Relations, 1977-1979 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - South African Labour News [publication of the African American Labour Center), 1982-1983 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - South African Summary [vol. 2, no. 8), 1963 February 22 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Spark [news series, vol. 1, nos. 23-29], 1963 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Town data [publication of Pienaar and Associates, pvt. ltd subtitled "inhabited places in the Republic of South Africa, South West Africa, Lesotho, Botswana and Swaziland"], 1968 May (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - "TV Index" [report on viewing habits in the Republic of South Africa], 1977 September-December (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - United Nations Center Against Apartheid, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - University of the Witwatersrand [African studies seminar papers], 1987, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - War Resisters League (Illinois), 1985 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - X-ray [quick fact sheet on current affairs in South Africa], 1977 Mar/April (Box 2, Folder 42)
- Additional Material, 1961-1990; Accession 2011-M-001
  - Assorted Publications
    - Address by State President P.W. Botha on the occasion of the opening of the third session of the eighth parliament of the Republic of South Africa, 1986 January 31 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Friends of Moses Mayekiso Newsletter, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - ASSA: Deportations, detentions and disturbance: notes towards a contemporary history of the universities of Bophuthatswana and Transkei, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - The South African Institute of International Affairs: biennial meeting of the National Executive Committee, 1978 May 19 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - The South African Institute of International Affairs: memo to all members, 1976 October (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - The South African Institute of International Affairs (SAIA): "Role of the SAIA", Undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Annexure to the chairman's report: the activities of the S.A. Institute of International Affairs, 1978 May 19 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Cape Town historical walks: Central City, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Contact, 1961 March (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Sewentig, 1971 April 27 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Afrique Australe Infos - Femmes d'Afrique Australe, 1983 December (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - "The Two Kennedys": Brochure from the Historical Society of the University of Durban-Westville, 1971 October (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - University of Fort Hare brochure, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - The Southern African Institute of International Affairs (booklet), 1971 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - The Africa Fund: Annual Report, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Indaba: Inside the ANC, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - National Union of South African Students (pamphlet), Undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - The Azanian Labour Journal, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Clarion Call: Black Unity Who Wants it?, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Economic Crisis in South Africa, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Fact paper on Southern Africa, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Focus (two copies), 1989 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - From Tokyo to Johannesburg, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - "Homeland" tragedy: function and farce, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - How They Hate Us, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Openingsrede, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Perspective: College Actions on South African Investments, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Philosophy and Class Struggle, Undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Resister, Undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - The Center for Intergroup Studies, A Review of the First Ten Years, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - RSA Update (four copies), 1989 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Sahara Libre, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - SASPU Focus (two copies), 1986 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - SASPU National (two copies), 1988 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - South African Outlook (four copies), 1988 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Voice of Women, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - What Trade Unions are Saying, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Apartheid-Related Publications
    - Are you banking on apartheid? (Anti-apartheid pamphlet) (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - United States Information Agency -talking paper (office of the assistant director for Africa), 1971 September (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Fifth Summit Conference of East and Central African States -Lusaka Manifesto, 1969 April (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - United States Options in Southern Africa -Address by David D. Newsom, assistant secretary for African affairs, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - United States Information Agency -transcripts of the press conference of asst. secretary of state Newsom and deputy asst. secretary of state Carter in Johannesburg, 1970 November (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Department Reviews US position on Southern Rhodesia -Statement by David Newsom, asst. secretary for African affairs, 1971 July (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Memorandum illustrating US-South Africa trade statistics, 1971 September (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Current Foreign Policy: US Role in African Development, 1972 September (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - The Africa Fund (associated with the American Committee on Africa) -the coloured protest in South Africa, 1980 April-May (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - National Committee Against Removals (NCAR): comments on the white paper and new legislation on urbanization, Undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Southern African News Agency -Sana Bulletin (2 copies), 1980 May (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Chicago Committee in Solidarity with Southern Africa (CCSSA): briefing, spring 1988 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Press statement from Surplus People Project (W. Cape), 1985 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Africa Press Service -Features: South Africa, Botha blames Press, 1987 September (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - APS News and Features Bulletin: SA stops court case over detainees, 1984 May (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - APS News and Features Bulletin: Sexism branded as sin, 1988 May (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - APS News and Features Bulletin: Pope warns media against misuse of its power, 1988 February (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - World Campaign Against Military and Nuclear Collaboration with South Africa, 1987 February (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - World Campaign Against Military and Nuclear Collaboration with South Africa (UN international seminar on: the implementation and reinforcement of the arms embargo against South Africa), 1981 April (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - US-Congo Friendship Committee: Action Alert, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Southscan, Bulletin of Southern African Affairs, 1988 July (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Mozambique News Agency (AIM) Feature: Botha on the defensive, 1984 June (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - South African Education Program (Newsletter), 1986 August (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - American African Affairs Association: Spotlight on Africa, 1982 July-August (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - American African Affairs Association: Spotlight on Africa, 1984 November-December (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - American African Affairs Association: Spotlight on Africa, 1985 January-February (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - African Bureau Fact Sheet 24: South Africa's Judiciary, 1972 December (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Facing the emergency, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - War Resisters League: emergency inside South Africa -resisting apartheid and war, 1987 May (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Emergency inside South Africa: an end conscription campaign report, 1987 February (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - South African Institute of Race Relations (SAIRR), topical briefing: African metric results -1955 to 1983, 1984 may (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - South African Institute of Race Relations (SAIRR), topical briefing: How the tax law affects blacks, 1984 May (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Speech by Mr. Irving Brown, US Workers Delegate to the 66th session of the International Labor Conference in Geneva, 1984 May (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - South African Institute of Race Relations (SAIRR), topical briefing: analysis of some of the key points in the report of the national manpower commission (NMC) on collective bargaining and related matters, 1984 May (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - "Education For All" newsletter, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - African Supplement: "Slavery" on South Africa's white owned farms? ILO, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Presentation for the International Development Conference, 1987 March (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Association of Third World Affairs: third world forum, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Picture from South African Outlook (peaceful high school student protest), 1976 August (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - IMADR Bulletin: International Movement Against All Forms of Discrimination and Racism (2 copies), 1988 April (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - American Committee on Africa -South Africa: friends and foes, 1971 October (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - American Committee on Africa -US groups support South African student protests, 1972 June (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Aurora Associates Inc: South African Higher Education Program, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - My experiences and impact of the South African aggressions in Botswana, Maureen Diemo Magole, 1988 November (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Repression Monitoring Group: the week that was ...., 1989 August 7-13 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Life history of the late Mr. Trevor Vilakazi, 1990 August (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - South African Students Committee (SASCO), 1988 February (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - West Virginia Public Radio Commentary, 1988 June 14 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Victoria De Lee campaign for congress material, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Voice of America -Journal of Defense and Diplomacy, 1983 December (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Remarks of Sen. Edward M. Kennedy of Massachusetts at the J.F.K. Presidential Conference at Hofstra University, New York, 1985 March 29 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - South African Pamphlets on Islam
    - Awake to the call of Islam, 1983 December (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Status of women in Islam, 1982 March (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Love, brotherhood and equality in Islam, 1982 March (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - The dynamism of Islam, 1982 March (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Islamic Pardah: English At-Tableeg No. 6, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Gulzare Asharaf: At-Tableeg No. 86, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - US-South Africa Business Ties
    - Investment in apartheid: list of companies with investment and interests in South Africa, 1974 May (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Constraints and opportunities facing the re-emergence of the black trade union movement in South Africa, 1977 June (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Department of State: the climate for doing business in South Africa, 1977 April (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Employment practices of US firms on South Africa, Building business with Africa (Dun's Review), 1973 February (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Kennecott Cooper Corp: summary of the annual meeting of stockholders, 1977 March (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Backgrounder (United States Information Service): US example may move world business against apartheid, 1977 June (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - SAIRR: United States corporate investment and social change in South Africa, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - South Africa perspectives: prospects for change -apartheid and the African worker, Undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - South Africa perspectives: too little too late, 1977 April (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - American Consulate General, Johannesburg, SA: Commercial Section, Undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Department of State, bureau of African affairs: Employment practices of US in South Africa, 1973 February (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Mining Interests During Apartheid
    - Tubatse magazine, Undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - NCNB Loans to South Africa: Rumours of R95m secret loan to SA, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Princeton Alumni Weekly: University investments and South Africa, 1978 May 22 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Looking at a gold mine in South Africa (pamphlet), Undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Turning the gold mines to green (William Cook, manager of the vegetation unit of the Chamber of Mines of South Africa), Undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Sky's the limit (a publication of the Chamber of Mines of South Africa), Undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Additional material, 1952-1987; Accession 2015-M-001
  - Printed material, 1952-1987 (Box 1, Folder 1-2)